<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Cai | Blog</title>
    <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Cai | Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://davidcai.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Dawn</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/a-new-dawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/a-new-dawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is the end of an era. After almost 8-year service at Financial Engines, I decided to advance my career in a different place. The decision is definitely not easy. Leaving FE is like carving away a big chunk of my life. So many familiar faces, so many beautiful memories. However, as of today, I still believe that when facing a great opportunity, I&amp;rsquo;d rather give it my best try than having the regrets of inaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to be a part of this great journey. During these 8 years, we went though two waves of technology evolutions at FE. Each time we pushed forward closer to adopting a modern front-end technology stack. The past two years are the most exciting for app developers at FE. Single Page Application (SPA) had its debut. Macbook was introduced to wider audience. SPA CICD pipeline was born at that time. Git, Gulp, Bower, Node JS, Optimizely, SauceLabs, App Dynamics, Analytics, Loggly, Jasmine, Protractor, and C3/D3 all happened within that short period. Things just got exploded &amp;hellip; in a good way :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/ui-revolution.png&#34; alt=&#34;UI revolution&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m confident to make an assertion that our front-end technologies of today can compete head to head with any unicorn company&amp;rsquo;s. We certainly have technical difficulties here and there, but overall, the teams are much better equipped compared to what we had one year ago. All thanks to the great people here who made this happen. I&amp;rsquo;m honored to ride the journey together with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/ui-tech-stack.png&#34; alt=&#34;Front end tech stack&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my last day at FE, looking forward, I see FE has a bright future on the tech horizon. We might adopt Angular 2 or React JS, and TypeScript or ES6. Micro-service started steadily with backend code componentization. More people had their taste of AWS Lambda. Folks at Platforms did great work on APIGEE. And soon, we will have our first mobile app implemented in React Native. It is an exciting time for exploration and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow will be a new dawn for me, and certainly Financial Engines will see a bright future ahead. I have confidence in me and in you. Wish all of us the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodbye, my friends, for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Framework at Financial Engines</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/why-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/why-serverless/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When working with Amazon Lambda, my colleagues asked what benefits we will reap from using the Serverless framework. We can directly code Lambda functions in AWS&amp;rsquo; online editor, or upload a zip file to AWS if the Lambda function requires any 3rd-party node modules. The workflow might be tedious but quite easy to understand. So why Serverless?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people new to Lambda, the amount of concepts introduced by Serverless could be overwhelming &amp;ndash; CloudFormation templates, Serverless&amp;rsquo;s S3 bucket, stages, Lambda function configurations, and Serverless&amp;rsquo; commands. At the early stage of JAWS (Serverless&amp;rsquo; previous brand name), I even found the framework is very opinionated in some way. So I tried to come up with my own solution &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidcai/lambda-gulp&#34;&gt;a collection of gulp tasks&lt;/a&gt; that automate CloudFormation and Lambda function deployment. The funny thing is that during the development of these Gulp scripts, I start to have better understanding of the Lambda development workflow, and appreciate more of what Serverless is trying to achieve. Understanding the aforementioned concepts are actually crucial to develop scalable Lambda projects. I stopped working on my own solution just before JAWS had a major release which re-branded the framework to Serverless, and brought in many needed features. And from then, I picked up Serverless again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-serverless-gave-us:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;What Serverless gave us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about Serverless framework is that it incorporates many good practices that might seem to be over-complicate for simple projects, but will exponentially accelerate the development cycle for mid and large projects. Sure, there are many other tools and plugins that support Lambda development and deployment, such as Jenkins&amp;rsquo; Lambda plugin, and ThoughtWorks&amp;rsquo; node module &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ThoughtWorksStudios/node-aws-lambda&#34;&gt;node-aws-lambda&lt;/a&gt;. But so far, Serverless is still one of the very few popular frameworks that handle the full development cycle of Lambda, API Gateway, and other AWS resources. The Serverless CLI can be integrated with CICD pipelines such as Jenkins (which we do at Financial Engines) that further automates the workflow. I found Serverless is especially useful in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-local-development:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;1. Local Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding directly in AWS Lambda editor might be OK for small projects, but it is not fitting for any project larger than hello world examples. Having Lambda functions developed in local is essential to have an efficient working setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers are able to version control the local Lambda code. With Serverless framework, configurations including API Gateway endpoint definitions and CloudFormation templates can also be version controlled (more about CloudFormation later).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers can run local unit test before deploying the Lambda function. The new features coming to Serverless even enables local test of REST API endpoints together with Lambda functions. Greatly increased the chance to catch bugs before the actual deployment. Also, made local debugging feasible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can even pre-process the JavaScript code, e.g. linting. AWS Lambda doesn&amp;rsquo;t support ES6 yet, but we can set up transpiler such as Babel in the local development environment to transpile ES6 down to ES5.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-scaffolding:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;2. Scaffolding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Serverless CLI, creating projects is just a command away. The &lt;code&gt;serverless project create&lt;/code&gt; command prepares the local project structures, generates default CloudFormation template, and creates IAM roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command also sets up a S3 bucket to hoist the bundled Lambda source code, environment variables, and CloudFormation templates. All of them are timestamped and nicely organized in their corresponding stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating new Lambda functions can be easily done via &lt;code&gt;serverless function create&lt;/code&gt;, which generates the function structure, sample Lambda code, event mockup for local test, and function-level configuration file where the API endpoint will be defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this made Lambda development much easy to kick off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-cloudformation:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;3. CloudFormation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CloudFormation template is a JSON file that declares AWS resources required by a project. The benefit of having a template is that we can use the same template to duplicate the creation of AWS resources in different stages and regions. The picture below illustrated the relationships among regions, stages, Lambda functions, API endpoints, and other AWS resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/aws-stages.png&#34; alt=&#34;Stages&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(L = Lambda function, E = API endpoint)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, our project needs to access a S3 bucket, and such bucket has its own bucket policy. Instead of manually setting up the S3 bucket and a bucket policy for each region and stage, we can declare S3 bucket and its policy in a CloudFormation template. Then, the AWS CloudFormation service will automate the resource creation by honoring the declarations in the template. This configuration driven approach is much easier to scale up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CloudFormation is the core part of the Serverless framework. Serverless relies on CloudFormation to manage AWS resources required by both the Serverless framework and project. Resources used by Serverless itself includes IAM policies, roles, log access, and Serverless&amp;rsquo; S3 bucket. Resources required by projects could be DynamoDB, S3, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serverless provided &lt;code&gt;serverless resources deploy&lt;/code&gt; command that will validate the CloudFormation template, check if the template is changed, update the CloudFormation stack if there is any change, or create the stack if the stack doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, and track the CloudFormation creation/updating status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CloudFormation is a powerful service that needs to be understood not only for Lambda development but also other AWS resource management. The Serverless framework fully embraces this service and makes the usage really easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, all these CloudFormation operations can be achieved using AWS CLI or SDK. Actually, I attempted duplicating Serverless features by creating my own Gulp tasks that leverage AWS SDK to perform CloudFormation validation, deployment, and status tracking. It is definitely doable. But I don&amp;rsquo;t like to re-invent wheels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-api-gateway-endpoint:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;4. API Gateway Endpoint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, CloudFormation still cannot be used to define AWS API Gateway endpoints. Serverless framework tries to close this gap. It allows API endpoints to be defined in JSON files. The &lt;code&gt;serverless function create&lt;/code&gt; command generates a default configuration file, and the &lt;code&gt;serverless endpoint deploy&lt;/code&gt; command will use the configuration to create and deploy the API endpoints in Gateway. (For more examples, check my other &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/serverless-and-cors/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;d love to see is the ability to use Swagger to define API endpoints instead of the current ad hoc syntax. Hope the Serverless team will pick this up in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-i-d-love-to-have:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;Things I&amp;rsquo;d love to have&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-multiple-aws-account-support:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;1. Multiple AWS account support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like other young software, Serverless certainly has room for improvement. One thing I&amp;rsquo;d really love to have is the support for deploying AWS resources in multiple AWS accounts. Currently, Serverless embraces Stages for promoting builds from development to test, and then from test to production. Each build environment is a &amp;lsquo;stage&amp;rsquo;, and they all live in one AWS account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at Financial Engines, we have three AWS accounts &amp;ndash; dev, test, and prod. We&amp;rsquo;d like to promote builds from dev account to test account, and to prod account without bothering with stages. This three layers of accounts is actually quite common practice in IT. However, since Serverless doesn&amp;rsquo;t support multiple AWS accounts yet, we have to rely on stages. We ended up with something like this in order to promote builds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/serverless-what-we-have.png&#34; alt=&#34;Build promotion using stages&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, we have code and resources deployed in one AWS account &amp;ndash; prod; and inside this account, code is promoted from stage development to test, and then to production. We are not using the other two AWS accounts &amp;ndash; dev and test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This practice seems to be working, however, it has one issue. AWS accounts often have different permissions. Dev account is usually set up for developers and has more generous access policies. With these generous policies, developers are able to login to AWS Dev account, and inspect or even change deployed resources (e.g., Lambda functions, and API endpoints). On the contrary, the Prod account will have more restricted access policies. Developers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to login to the Prod account and mess around. This access might be granted to System Admin or Release Engineers. Since we deploy all resources to the Prod account &amp;ndash; the one with strict policies, developers will not have credentials to login to that account, and thus lost the ability to inspect or modify the deployed resources. Certainly, we can grant developers the read permission. There is some workaround we can do. But still it seems that the stage promotion within one AWS account doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit very well with the environment that leverages multiple AWS accounts to promote builds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we would love to have is something like this instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/serverless-what-we-need.png&#34; alt=&#34;Build promotion using accounts&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No stage promotions but cross-account promotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t played around the Project Variables &amp;ndash; the newly introduced feature. Not sure if this new feature can be harnessed to solve the multiple account problem. If anyone has experience with this, please let me know :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-session-token-support:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;2. Session token support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AWS SDK supports Session Token &amp;ndash; a token that will expire after a certain period, and will be used together with access ID and secrete access key for AWS authentication. This is extremely useful for maintaining large number of IDs and keys. Since Session Token will simply expire, there is much less need to actively delete unused/obsolete IDs or keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I checked, Serverless hasn&amp;rsquo;t incorporated the support for Session Token yet. Would love to have that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serverless-framework-alternatives:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;Serverless framework alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like every framework, it might solve 80% of your problems, but to get the other 20%, things might turn to exponentially difficult, to a point, you even feel like fighting against the framework :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dislike framework that &amp;lsquo;dictates&amp;rsquo; your workflow, here are some alternatives to the Serverless framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ThoughtWorksStudios/node-aws-lambda&#34;&gt;node-aws-lambda&lt;/a&gt; from ThoughtWorks studio. It is a Node module to automate the AWS Lambda function deployment. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t include API endpoint deployment. But with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awslabs/aws-apigateway-importer&#34;&gt;AWS API Gateway Importer&lt;/a&gt; from AWS lab, you can create or update API endpoints from a Swagger or RAML document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For editing CloudFormation templates, IntelliJ has a plugin &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7371?pr=idea&#34;&gt;AWS CloudFormation support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My unfinished &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidcai/lambda-gulp/blob/master/gulp/lambda.js&#34;&gt;Gulp script project&lt;/a&gt; has some interesting Gulp tasks to validate and upload CloudFormation templates. Deleting, updating, describing stacks, and tracking stack update progress are also included. I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked on this project for a while, but I believe the majority of the code still work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:21a5a79a44a185553300308dba71ec54&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serverless framework is still young, yet it already brought us useful features that simplified the Lambda development. It certainly has room for improvement. The early product feels more limiting in how to organize and name your code assets. The later development has made some parts of this framework more configurable and thus flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many times when I questioned myself if we should come up with something else rather than adopting this young and fast changing framework. Our current approach is to stay the course with Serverless. I just feel that it is too early to deviate away from &amp;lsquo;the Serverless way&amp;rsquo;. Like I said, the framework has some good practices baked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anything is missing, the framework authors and contributors are quite diligent to close the gap. There are 44 contributors after all. The other approach is to contribute to the framework by ourselves. This is what we did at Financial Engines &amp;ndash; fork the source, implement a new feature, then submit a pull request. It is a very open-source way to fix issues for ourselves and at the meanwhile evolve the framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the worst scenario, even when we decide to &amp;lsquo;stray away&amp;rsquo; from this Serverless framework, we&amp;rsquo;ve already learned a ton along the way. The journey itself is worth it. And at that time, we might have articulated enough intelligence to confidently develop our own solutions. So far, I feel this time is still far away. The framework is at pre-release stage, and constantly improving. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend checking out its new features, and involving the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Framework &amp; AWS API Gateway CORS</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/serverless-and-cors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/serverless-and-cors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run into HTTP errors related to &amp;lsquo;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&amp;rsquo; when calling a REST API endpoint through the AWS API Gateway, you probably need to enable CORS (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing) for your endpoint methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS has a well written &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/apigateway/latest/developerguide/how-to-cors.html&#34;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; describing how to enable CORS in the API Gateway UI. However, if you&amp;rsquo;d like to leverage the Serverless framework to automatically create API endpoints for you, including CORS settings, this article has an example of the Serverless configuration (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Serverless configuration file you want to modify is at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;serverless project&amp;gt;/back/modules/&amp;lt;module&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;function&amp;gt;/s-function.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the comment-annotated configurations from the snippet below. Please note if you copy the content to your s-function.json, remove all comments and empty lines; otherwise, the JSON probably will be invalid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;{
  &amp;quot;functions&amp;quot;: {
    &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot;: {
      &amp;quot;custom&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;excludePatterns&amp;quot;: [],
        &amp;quot;envVars&amp;quot;: []
      },
      &amp;quot;handler&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;modules/greetings/hello/handler.handler&amp;quot;,
      &amp;quot;timeout&amp;quot;: 6,
      &amp;quot;memorySize&amp;quot;: 1024,
      &amp;quot;events&amp;quot;: [
        {
          &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;default&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;eventSourceArn&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;startingPosition&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;TRIM_HORIZON&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;batchSize&amp;quot;: 100,
          &amp;quot;enabled&amp;quot;: true
        }
      ],
      &amp;quot;endpoints&amp;quot;: [
        {
          // Your API endpoint path
          &amp;quot;path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;greetings/hello&amp;quot;,

          // Method could be POST, DELETE, etc, depending on your API schema
          &amp;quot;method&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;GET&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;authorizationType&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;apiKeyRequired&amp;quot;: false,
          &amp;quot;requestParameters&amp;quot;: {},
          &amp;quot;requestTemplates&amp;quot;: {

            // Your endpoint method probably doesn&#39;t need this mapping
            &amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;{\&amp;quot;name\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;$input.params(&#39;name&#39;)\&amp;quot;}&amp;quot;
          },
          &amp;quot;responses&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;400&amp;quot;: {
              &amp;quot;statusCode&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;400&amp;quot;
            },
            &amp;quot;default&amp;quot;: {
              &amp;quot;statusCode&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,

              // [start] Add the following response parameters for response 200. This will enable CORS for this GET method.
              &amp;quot;responseParameters&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;method.response.header.Access-Control-Allow-Headers&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&#39;Content-Type,X-Amz-Date,Authorization,X-Api-Key,Cache-Control&#39;&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;method.response.header.Access-Control-Allow-Methods&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&#39;*&#39;&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;method.response.header.Access-Control-Allow-Origin&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&#39;*&#39;&amp;quot;
              },
              &amp;quot;responseModels&amp;quot;: {},
              &amp;quot;responseTemplates&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
              }
              // [end]
            }
          }
        },

        // [start] Add the OPTIONS method required by CORS.
        {
          &amp;quot;path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;greetings/hello&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;method&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;OPTIONS&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;authorizationType&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;,
          &amp;quot;apiKeyRequired&amp;quot;: false,
          &amp;quot;requestParameters&amp;quot;: {},
          &amp;quot;requestTemplates&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;\&amp;quot;statusCode\&amp;quot;: 200&amp;quot;
          },
          &amp;quot;responses&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;default&amp;quot;: {
              &amp;quot;statusCode&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,
              &amp;quot;responseParameters&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;method.response.header.Access-Control-Allow-Headers&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&#39;Content-Type,X-Amz-Date,Authorization,X-Api-Key,Cache-Control&#39;&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;method.response.header.Access-Control-Allow-Methods&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&#39;*&#39;&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;method.response.header.Access-Control-Allow-Origin&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&#39;*&#39;&amp;quot;
              },
              &amp;quot;responseModels&amp;quot;: {},
              &amp;quot;responseTemplates&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;
              }
            }
          }
        }
        // [end]
      ]
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you added required configuration to enable CORS, run the Serverless command to deploy the endpoint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;serverless function deploy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to AWS API Gateway, you should be able to see that CORS is now enabled for the endpoint method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Multiple Java Versions on Mac</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/install-multiple-jdk-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/install-multiple-jdk-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;During one of AWS Lambda exploration projects, I need to use Amazon&amp;rsquo;s swagger-import-tool for uploading swagger documents to AWS. The problem is that this tool has a dependency on Java 8, however, my installed JDK is 7, and I have to keep it for all existing Java projects. It seems that I need to have something like NVM (Node Version Manager) &amp;hellip; this time for JDKs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some Google searches, a promising solution is to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jenv.be/&#34;&gt;jEnv&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; a command line tool to set JAVA_HOME on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;homebrew-cask:677a9bde6e1ad5d989b759e109310067&#34;&gt;Homebrew Cask&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mac, Homebrew is the de-facto package manager, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://gillesfabio.github.io/homebrew-cask-homepage/&#34;&gt;Homebrew Cask&lt;/a&gt; is the app manager. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use Cask to install Java 7 and 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Homebrew Cask first if you haven&amp;rsquo;t:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew update
brew tap caskroom/cask
brew install brew-cask
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your brew or cask is outdated, update and upgrade:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew upgrade brew-cask &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew cleanup &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew cask cleanup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-java-7-and-8:677a9bde6e1ad5d989b759e109310067&#34;&gt;Install Java 7 and 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People on the Stackoverflow cautioned &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to install 8 until 7 is installed. So we are going to install JDK 7 first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other version managers such as NVM, jEnv itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t install JDKs. You have to do it yourself. Luckily, Homebrew Cask made this task really easy. But before doing that, let&amp;rsquo;s check if we already have JDK 7 installed by Homebrew Cask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew tap caskroom/versions
brew cask info java7
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Java 7 is installed, you should see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/brew-cask-info-java7.png&#34; alt=&#34;brew cask info java7&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, install Java 7:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew cask install java7
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into permission issue, add &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of the above command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, Java 8 is the latest stable. Run the following command to install Java 8:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew cask install java
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two JDKs will be installed at the following directories. Your JDKs&amp;rsquo; minor and patch versions might be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.7.0_79.jdk/Contents/Home/
/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.8.0_66.jdk/Contents/Home/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enter-jenv:677a9bde6e1ad5d989b759e109310067&#34;&gt;Enter jEnv&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is time to install jEnv:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew install jenv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the following lines to ~/.bash_profile. This will initialize jEnv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Init jenv
if which jenv &amp;gt; /dev/null; then eval &amp;quot;$(jenv init -)&amp;quot;; fi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jEnv doesn&amp;rsquo;t install JDKs, so we have to tell jEnv where to look for them. Type these commands to register JDKs in jEnv (replace the minor and patch versions with yours):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jenv add /Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.7.0_79.jdk/Contents/Home/
jenv add /Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.8.0_66.jdk/Contents/Home/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, run this command to list all registered JDKs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jenv versions
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output will be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/jenv-versions.png&#34; alt=&#34;brew cask info java7&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The version with an asterisk is the active version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I need to keep JDK 7 as my default version, so I set the global version to 1.7:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jenv global oracle64-1.7.0.79
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in my project, I set the local JDK version to 1.8:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cd &amp;lt;my project&amp;gt;
jenv local oracle64-1.8.0.66
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above command will create a &lt;code&gt;.java-version&lt;/code&gt; file at project root. Its content is the version I just picked for this project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;oracle64-1.8.0.66
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references:677a9bde6e1ad5d989b759e109310067&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about jEnv, here I list some references:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jEnv &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jenv.be/&#34;&gt;official site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26252591/mac-os-x-and-multiple-java-versions&#34;&gt;Stackoverflow thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew John&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrew-jones.com/blog/managing-multiple-versions-of-java-on-os-x/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom Essential Packages</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/my-favorite-atom-editor-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/my-favorite-atom-editor-plugins/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Atom &amp;ndash; the hackable editor coming from Github has been my favorite for web development. Like many other lightweight editors, Atom has a community-driven packages (plugins) marketplace that greatly enhanced the editor. I found the following Atom packages are essential to my web development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-manager:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;Project-manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package is a lifesaver for people like me who often need to work with more than one projects. Project-manager saves your project in a registry. Switching to other saved projects is just one key shortcut away - &lt;code&gt;cmd + ctrl + p&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/project-manager.png&#34; alt=&#34;Project Manager&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pigments:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;Pigments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to styling, colors might be the most important factor. It will be nice to see the actual color defined by color values right in the editor. The Pigments package gives you just that. All color values will be decorated with a block of their correspondent colors in the same file. You have options to select different decoration styles. For me, &amp;ldquo;sqaure-dot&amp;rdquo; worked the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;img-og&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/pigments.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlight-selected:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;Highlight-selected&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Atom, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to highlight all occurrences that matches my current selection. For example, I selected &amp;ldquo;export&amp;rdquo; and would like to immediately see all &amp;ldquo;reports&amp;rdquo; are highlighted in the current file. I consider this basic functionality should be included in Atom but sadly it isn&amp;rsquo;t. Highlight-selected fixed that. You can choose to highlight the border or the background. The package even comes with two highlight colors - one for dark background, and the other for light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;img-og&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/highlight-selected.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;editorconfig:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;EditorConfig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you suffered from other developers&amp;rsquo; bad habits of using a mix of tabs, spaces, charset, trailing white spaces and lines? EditorConfig.org created a standard to promote a consistent coding styles between different editors and IDEs. Their website maintained &lt;a href=&#34;http://editorconfig.org/#download&#34;&gt;a list of plugins&lt;/a&gt; that support this standard. All you need to do is to define a &lt;code&gt;.editorconfig&lt;/code&gt; file at the root of your project, and download the plugin. Then, your editor will recognize &lt;code&gt;.editorconfig&lt;/code&gt; and start to apply the styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of .editorconfig file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# http://editorconfig.org
root = true

[*]
indent_style = space
indent_size = 2
end_of_line = lf
charset = utf-8
trim_trailing_whitespace = true
insert_final_newline = true

[*.md]
trim_trailing_whitespace = false

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tabs-to-spaces:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;Tabs-to-spaces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found editorconfig itself is not enough to convert all tab indentations to spaces. I had to use this tabs-to-spaces package for that. Like the name suggested, this package transforms all tabs indentations to spaces, or vice versa. In the package&amp;rsquo;s setting UI, you have the option to choose &amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;tabify&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;untabify&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo; does nothing; &amp;ldquo;tabify&amp;rdquo; changes indentations in spaces to tabs; and &amp;ldquo;untabify&amp;rdquo; does the opposite - replacing tabs with spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;linter-and-linter-eslint:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;Linter and linter-eslint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hobby projects, you might don&amp;rsquo;t care about linting. However, for me, even hobby projects could use some code static analysis. linter and linter-eslint shout out loud whenever (most of the time) I make syntax mistakes. They saved me tons of time that would have been wasted in JavaScript debugging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/eslint.png&#34; alt=&#34;Eslint&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes:d55c2485435fe256bf1d0dbed34987bb&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how bad our art taste are, we developers do care about our color themes in editor, don&amp;rsquo;t we? Since this is a very subjective area, I will leave the theme picking to yourself. However, here I just want to shamelessly introduce to you my own syntax theme majorly emphasizing on green, brown, white, and blue, designed for web app coding - the theme color for Druids in World of Warcraft, hence the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/emerald-dream-syntax-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Emerald Dream Syntax&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme is not published as an Atom package yet, however, you can still get it from Github:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidcai/emerald-dream-syntax&#34;&gt;https://github.com/davidcai/emerald-dream-syntax&lt;/a&gt;. Git clone to ~/.atom/packages/ directory, reload Atom, and then select Emerald Dream from the syntax themes dropdown list. This syntax theme works best with Atom Material UI theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, Emerald Dream or not, choose your own theme. The point is to make your editor more pleasant and effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on Promise and $http Service</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-promise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reviewing a lot of Angular code lately. One common problem I found is the unnecessary use of deferred object to resolve and reject promises. In this post, I will illustrate a simplified approach. Another problem is a mix of then, catch, two callbacks in then, success, and error. I will go through each, and propose adopting a single style that can also be applied when using other Promise libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resolve-promise:3ddbf3d50d77c978c68a9cd4e936397f&#34;&gt;Resolve Promise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following snippet uses $http service to make a REST call, and resolve the returned data from the response. This is a common pattern I often find in Angular code, however, the code is not optimal (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;/////////////////////////////////////////////////
// Not preferred. Unnecessary usage of deferred
/////////////////////////////////////////////////
function getUser($q, $http) {
  var deferred = $q.defer();

  $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(function(response) {
    deferred.resolve(response.data);
  });

  return $q.promise;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above code can be simplified to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//////////////
// Preferred
//////////////
function getUser($http) {
  return $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(function(response) {
    return response.data;
  });
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; function accepts three callbacks: successCallback, errorCallback, and notifyCallback. If you return a value in the successCallback or errorCallback, the returned value will be used to &lt;em&gt;resolve&lt;/em&gt; the promise. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to explicitly call &lt;code&gt;deferred.resolve(response.data)&lt;/code&gt; to resolve the promise. Instead, simply &lt;code&gt;return response.data&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s callback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; function returns a new promise, so no need to use &lt;code&gt;$q&lt;/code&gt; to create a deferred object and return its associated promise. Just return the promise created by &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reject-promise:3ddbf3d50d77c978c68a9cd4e936397f&#34;&gt;Reject Promise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about error handling? Using the not preferred example, we can call &lt;code&gt;deferred.reject&lt;/code&gt; in the error callback to reject the promise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;/////////////////////////////////////////////////
// Not preferred. Unnecessary usage of deferred
/////////////////////////////////////////////////
function getUser($q, $http) {
  var deferred = $q.defer();

  $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(
    function(response) { // Success callback
      deferred.resolve(response.data); // Resolve
    },
    function(response) { // Error callback
      deferred.reject(response); // Reject
    }
  );

  return $q.promise;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a simplified solution is again to use &lt;em&gt;return&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;reject&lt;/em&gt;. But, what shall we return? You probably think to return the response in the error callback like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;function getUser($http) {
  return $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(
    function(response) {
      return response.data;
    },
    function(response) { // Error callback
      return response; // &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; Wrong
      // Or return false; // &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; Still wrong
    }
  );
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, values returned from the successCallback or the errorCallback are considered to be resolved values for the promise. So the &lt;code&gt;return response&lt;/code&gt; in the error callback will resolve instead reject the promise. Even when the returned value is falsy, the falsy value will be considered as a resolved value. The correct way is to return a rejected promise using &lt;code&gt;$q.reject(response)&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//////////////
// Preferred
//////////////
function getUser($q, $http) {
  return $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(
    function(response) {
      return response.data;
    },
    function(response) { // Error callback
      return $q.reject(response); // Use $q.reject
    }
  );
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the errorCallback in &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; function, Promise has another method &amp;ndash; &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt; to take an error callback. I personally prefer the &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt; pair over the two callbacks in &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; for its readability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;///////////////////////
// Catch is preferred
///////////////////////
function getUser($q, $http) {
  return $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(
    function(response) {
      return response.data;
    }
  ).catch( // Catch
    function(response) {
      return $q.reject(response);
    }
  );
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above code, &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; is used only for success callback. A &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt; is basically a &lt;code&gt;then()&lt;/code&gt; without success callback &amp;ndash; &lt;code&gt;then(angular.noop, errorCallback)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference from &lt;code&gt;then(successCallback, errorCallback)&lt;/code&gt; is that &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt; is chained of the promise returned by &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt;. However, the errorCallback in &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; is chained of the original promise returned by &lt;code&gt;$http.get()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be advised that in IE8 &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt; has special meaning, so instead of the dot syntax, write &lt;code&gt;[&#39;catch&#39;]&lt;/code&gt;. Yes, in IE8, &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt; is the catch :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;/////////////////
// Catch in IE8
/////////////////
function getUser($q, $http) {
  return $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(
    function(response) {
      return response.data;
    }
  )[&#39;catch&#39;]( // Catch
    function(response) {
      return $q.reject(response);
    }
  );
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t need to handle the error in the &lt;code&gt;getUser&lt;/code&gt; function shown above, you can drop the entire error callback, and let &lt;code&gt;getUser&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s consuming code to handle the error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//////////////
// Preferred
//////////////
function getUser($q, $http) {
  return $http.get(&#39;...&#39;).then(function(response) {
    return response.data;
  });
}

// getUser&#39;s consuming code
getUser().then(
  function(data) { // Success callback
    // Do something about data
  },
  function(response) { // Error callback
    // Handle error state
  }
);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;success-and-error-in-http-service:3ddbf3d50d77c978c68a9cd4e936397f&#34;&gt;Success and Error in $http Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In old versions (1.3 and less) of Angular, $http service has two additional methods &amp;ndash; success() and error(), which are similar to then(), however, the subtle differences are important:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$http.get(&#39;&#39;)
  .success(function(data) {
    ...
  })
  .error(function(error) {
    ...
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two methods are deprecated in Angular 1.4 partially for the confusion they introduced. The first argument passed into &lt;code&gt;success&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;error&lt;/code&gt; callbacks is not the response object itself, instead, it is the data unwrapped from the response object. However, in &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; callback, you call &lt;code&gt;response.data&lt;/code&gt; to retrieve the data. Here is a comparative example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// Success method
$http.get(&#39;&#39;).success(function(data) {
  $log.log(data);
});

// Then method
$http.get(&#39;&#39;).then(function(response) {
  $log.log(response.data); // &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; See the difference?
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second difference is that unlike &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt;, neither &lt;code&gt;success&lt;/code&gt; nor &lt;code&gt;error&lt;/code&gt; will create and return new promises. The promise they return is the same HTTP promise from &lt;code&gt;$http.get()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend not using &lt;code&gt;success&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;error&lt;/code&gt;, but adopting &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;catch&lt;/code&gt;. The latter can be found in other Promise libraries, and is already evolved to be a convention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:3ddbf3d50d77c978c68a9cd4e936397f&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usage of a deferred object to resolve and reject promises can be replaced by a simplified style:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning a value in success or error callbacks resolves the promise with the returned value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning a rejected promise using &lt;code&gt;return $q.reject(something)&lt;/code&gt; rejects the promise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prefer using catch to provide error callbacks. Change &lt;code&gt;.catch&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;[&#39;catch&#39;]&lt;/code&gt; in IE8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop using &lt;code&gt;success&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;error&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular Tutorial Videos</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here is my collection of free tutorial videos. Could be really helpful for people new to Angular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-shaping-up-with-angular-js:44f7cb680bd7f49bb2adaeef5a9fd994&#34;&gt;1. Shaping up with Angular JS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gregg Pollack&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Shaping up with Angular.js&amp;rdquo; from codeschool.com has been there for a while. It is one of the tutorials that have the best intro. The series covers Angular setup, binding, controllers, directives, filters, form handling, and services. The best part is its challenges after each chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;img-og&#34; href=&#34;http://campus.codeschool.com/courses/shaping-up-with-angular-js/intro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://projector.codeschool.com/videos/6ab6e1ab/thumbnail&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorial might be a bit confusing to navigate. Make sure you scroll all the way to the top, and click the &amp;ldquo;START COURSE&amp;rdquo; button, which will list all the chapters. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended starting from the beginning in the order. The tutorial walks you through building a gem store project. Skipping the previous chapters might make yourself lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom right corner, you will find the &amp;ldquo;START CHALLENGES&amp;rdquo; button which brings you to the exercises. The challenge mode gives you an inline editor to play around the code. Your editing will be immediately reflected in the &amp;ldquo;Preview&amp;rdquo; panel. Pretty handy for learn by play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorial has a sequel &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Staying Sharp with Angular.js&amp;rdquo;. Alyssa Nicoll will be your mentor. The first chapter covers router. It is free. The following chapters might need payment to unlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;http://campus.codeschool.com/courses/shaping-up-with-angular-js/intro&#34;&gt;Shaping up with Angular.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sequel: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeschool.com/courses/staying-sharp-with-angular-js&#34;&gt;Staying Sharp with Angular.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-egghead-io-new-to-angular-js:44f7cb680bd7f49bb2adaeef5a9fd994&#34;&gt;2. Egghead IO - New to Angular JS?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egghead is famous of its bite-sized videos. Each video can be consumed within 10 min. The entire tutorial is very easy to navigate. The noteworthy is that each short clip has its own discussion section. You might very well learn something new from these informative discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;img-og&#34; href=&#34;https://egghead.io/articles/new-to-angularjs-start-learning-here?utm_content=buffer3b17a&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.infragistics.com/community/cfs-file.ashx/__key/CommunityServer.Blogs.Components.WeblogFiles/brent_5F00_schooley.metablogapi/2061.logo_5F00_3309A602.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial spent a lot of inks on directives and isolated scopes, which are essential to writing better components in Angular JS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egghead.io is a powerhouse for all Angular learning. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to adventure to specific topics or advanced usage, check out this list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://egghead.io/technologies/angularjs&#34;&gt;all Angular lessons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egghead.io: &lt;a href=&#34;https://egghead.io/articles/new-to-angularjs-start-learning-here?utm_content=buffer3b17a&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34;&gt;New to AngularJS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-angular-youtube-channel:44f7cb680bd7f49bb2adaeef5a9fd994&#34;&gt;3. Angular Youtube Channel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who prefer picking their own lessons, Angular&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel is the gold mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;img-og&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/angularjs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://codegeekz.com/wp-content/uploads/AngularJS-YouTube.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strictly speaking, the channel itself is not a tutorial site, however, here, you will find great videos covering wide range of topics. I will give you some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julie Ralph&amp;rsquo;s video on Angular &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vvxsWokQblk&#34;&gt;Protractor test&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BvAeabvZ61o&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vojta Jina&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/rB5b67Cg6bc&#34;&gt;Testing Directives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/dF_ObGgzGE8&#34;&gt;Reusable Components in Angular: Design patterns, transclusion, and more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/angularjs&#34;&gt;Angular channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Youtube channels related to Angular JS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm9iiIfgmVODUJxINecHQkA&#34;&gt;ng-conf channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBWXtgwaUqyvI50euTYlUWQ&#34;&gt;Angular U channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-others:44f7cb680bd7f49bb2adaeef5a9fd994&#34;&gt;4. Others&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PluralSight.com &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pluralsight.com/search/?searchTerm=angular&#34;&gt;Angular courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/UlvCbnKAH3g&#34;&gt;John Papa - 10 AngularJS Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Mosher&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty8XcASK9js&#34;&gt;Advanced Directives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, some silly stuff &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/M_Wp-2XA9ZU&#34;&gt;ng-wat&lt;/a&gt; inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/FqhZZNUyVFM&#34;&gt;JS Wat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular: Copy vs. Extend vs. Merge</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/copy-vs-extend-vs-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/copy-vs-extend-vs-merge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Copy, extend, and merge are parts of the utility functions come with Angular. This post explores their differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;copy:1f01c150b870a11f9ba71472fb074eba&#34;&gt;Copy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.copy&lt;/code&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;var o1 = { name: &#39;David&#39;, age: 26, skill: {} };
var o2 = angular.copy(o1);

console.log(o2);
// Output: { name: &#39;David&#39;, age: 26, skill: {} }

console.log(o1 === o2);
// Output: false

console.log(o1.skill === o2.skill);
// Output: false
// o2.skill is a copy of o1.skill. They don&#39;t point to the same skill object.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extend:1f01c150b870a11f9ba71472fb074eba&#34;&gt;Extend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.extend(dst, src1, src2, ...)&lt;/code&gt; is to &lt;em&gt;shallow&lt;/em&gt; copy the properties of the source objects from right to left, all the way to the destination object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;var src1 = { name: &#39;David&#39;, age: 30 }; // source 1
var src2 = { age: 26, skill: {} }; // source 2
var dst = {}; // destination

console.log(angular.extend(dst, src1, src2));
// Output: { name: &#39;David&#39;, age: 26, skill: {} }

console.log(src2.skill === dst.skill);
// Output: true
// src2 and dst share the same skill object due to shallow copy.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;merge:1f01c150b870a11f9ba71472fb074eba&#34;&gt;Merge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt; is an Angular 1.4+ API that is to &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; (recursively) copy the properties of the source objects to the destination object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we use the above example, and replace &lt;code&gt;angular.extend&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;var src1 = { name: &#39;David&#39;, age: 30 };
var src2 = { age: 26, skill: {} };
var dst = {};

console.log(angular.merge(dst, src1, src2));
// Output: { name: &#39;David&#39;, age: 26, skill: {} }
// It seems to the same result as the previous example&#39;s, however, ...

console.log(src2.skill === dst.skill);
// Output: false
// src2.skill and dst.skill point to different skill objects due to deep copy.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-extend-vs-merge:1f01c150b870a11f9ba71472fb074eba&#34;&gt;More Extend vs. Merge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.copy&lt;/code&gt; is simply to clone an object. &lt;code&gt;angular.extend&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt; are more interesting. Here is another set of comparing examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.extend&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; shallow copy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;var src1 = { skill: { name: &#39;Java&#39;, experience: 20, certified: true } };
var src2 = { skill: { name: &#39;JavaScript&#39;, experience: 10 } };
var dst = {};

console.log(angular.extend(dst, src1, src2));
// Output: { skill: { name: &#39;JavaScript&#39;, experience: 10 } }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;certified: true&lt;/code&gt; is lost. Because of shallow copy, the skill property is &lt;em&gt;assigned&lt;/em&gt; from src2 to src1 without &lt;em&gt;recursively&lt;/em&gt; copying the individual properties inside the skill value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same code yields totally different result if we replace &lt;code&gt;extend&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;merge&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; deep (recursive) copy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;var src1 = { skill: { name: &#39;Java&#39;, experience: 20, certified: true } };
var src2 = { skill: { name: &#39;JavaScript&#39;, experience: 10 } };
var dst = {};

console.log(angular.merge(dst, src1, src2));
// Output: { skill: { name: &#39;JavaScript&#39;, experience: 10, certified: true } }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt;, properties are recursively copied from src2 to src1, so &lt;code&gt;certified: true&lt;/code&gt; is reserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-and-default-options:1f01c150b870a11f9ba71472fb074eba&#34;&gt;User and Default Options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.extend&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt; is often used to achieve user options overriding default options. Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;function orderDrink(options) {

  // Default options
  var defaultOptions = { size: &#39;medium&#39; };

  // Supplied options override default options
  var opts = angular.extend({}, defaultOptions, options);

  console.log(opts.size);
}

orderDrink({ size: &#39;large&#39; }); // Output: &#39;large&#39;
orderDrink(); // Output: &#39;medium&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more complicate case that has nested options, you might want to use &lt;code&gt;angular.merge&lt;/code&gt; for its deep copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webpack: Pack Your Web Assets</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-webpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/introducing-webpack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just had a presentation to introduce Webpack to our UI Guild in my company. Webpack is a module bundler to pack all kinds of web assets (JavaScript, styles, images, HTML partials, etc.) into one or more bundle JS files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1frBHDkSLvarbjFukhe3EuTuijpyTMHXwJDKu65OSVx8/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;my presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have highlighted the difference between Webpack and Require JS. Some developers are confused by these two tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Require JS (without using any plugin) sends a separate HTTP request to retrieve each dependency module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, Webpack is a pre-processor that bundles all required modules into one file before the bundle file is downloaded to users&amp;rsquo; browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Require JS apps load dependency on demand, but complicate apps with many dependencies tend to send a lot of requests which might impact performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webpack merges dependencies into one or more files, so the number of HTTP requests will be dramatically reduced, however, the initial download payload might be big. Webpack can be fine tuned to find a balance between the number of requests and download file size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how we can use Webpack to leverage Common JS module system to encapsulate dependency declarations in their requiring modules instead of flattening the dependency graph in the index.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, because tasks such as packaging, minification, source mapping, and transpiling can be done in Webpack, Gulp/Grunt scripts will be greatly simplified. And, we probably don&amp;rsquo;t even need Bower since almost all JS libraries can be installed from NPM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something remained to be tested are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How will Webpack solve library version conflicts? For instance, if Module A requires Angular 1.3 and Module B requires Angular 1.4, whether and how will Webpack help us solve the conflict? (Bower forces developers to manually resolve conflicts.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;UI Performance. With Webpack, style sheets will be imported through dynamically injected &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags, will this introduce flickering in UI? We have to test it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will come back to these questions once I run some tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple A/B Testing Service</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/a-simple-ab-testing-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/a-simple-ab-testing-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very simple A/B testing service implemented in Angular &amp;ndash; abTestService:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;;(function() {
  &#39;use strict&#39;;

  angular
    .module(&#39;abTest&#39;, [])
    .factory(&#39;abTestService&#39;, abTestService)
  ;


  function abTestService() {
    return {
      pick: pick
    };

    function pick() {
      var i = Math.floor(Math.random() * arguments.length);
      return arguments[i];
    }
  }

})();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;abTestService has only one method &amp;ndash; pick, which is to evenly pick one from many choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// a or b. 50% vs 50% chances
abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;);

// apple or orange. 50% vs 50%
abTestService.pick(&#39;apple&#39;, &#39;orange&#39;);

// a, b, or c. 1/3 vs 1/3 vs 1/3
abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;, &#39;c&#39;);

// a or b. 2/3 vs 1/3
abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of how to use abTestService with UI Router:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;;(function() {
  &#39;use strict&#39;;

  angular
    .module(&#39;myApp&#39;, [
      &#39;abTest&#39;,
      &#39;ui.router&#39;
    ])
    .config(configRoute)
  ;


  function configRoute($stateProvider) {
    $stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
      url: &#39;/&#39;,
      templateProvider: function(abTestService) { // Inject abTestService
        var result = abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;); // Pick a or b

        // home-a.html or home-b.html
        return &#39;&amp;lt;div ng-include=&amp;quot;\&#39;app/home-&#39; + result + &#39;.html\&#39;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#39;;
      }
    });
  }

})();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better explain the logic behind templateProvider, I created this &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/router-dynamic-templates/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Router: Dynamic Templates</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/router-dynamic-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/router-dynamic-templates/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post discusses how to create dynamic templates by leveraging the templateProvider configuration provided by Angular&amp;rsquo;s built-in router or the third-party UI Router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem:7c673880e38fa750461b975e7ddb6656&#34;&gt;PROBLEM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Single Page Applications (SPAs), we often need to switch views or states inside containers. This is usually done through routers. With either Angular&amp;rsquo;s built-in router or the popular UI Router, we are able to define the relationship between states and their templates. For instance, here we defined a state &lt;code&gt;home&lt;/code&gt; and its template URL &lt;code&gt;app/home/home.html&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;app.config(function($stateProvider) {
  $stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
    url: &#39;/&#39;,
    templateUrl: &#39;app/home/home.html&#39;
  });
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, this state-to-template relationship can not be determined beforehand at the &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt; time. The decision of what the template or template URL will be used for a state has to wait for the availability of run-time data. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User&amp;rsquo;s account type, e.g. show Home version A for members, and version B for public users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A/B testing, e.g. a A/B testing service randomly picks from two versions &amp;ndash; A or B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either scenario, the template cannot be fixed to &lt;code&gt;app/home/home.html&lt;/code&gt;, and has be to resolved using run-time data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Router&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;templateUrl&lt;/code&gt; configuration accepts a function which can be used to create dynamic template URL. However, we are not able to inject run-time dependencies (e.g. user services, or A/B test services) into the templateUrl function. The only available argument of the &lt;code&gt;templateUrl&lt;/code&gt; function is &lt;code&gt;$stateParams&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
  templateUrl: function($stateParams) { // Can not inject dependencies
    return &#39;app/home.&#39; + $stateParams.option + &#39;.html&#39;;
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution:7c673880e38fa750461b975e7ddb6656&#34;&gt;SOLUTION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is &lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Angular built-in router and the UI Router have a &lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt; configuration. &lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt; accepts a function that can be injected with run-time dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
  templateProvider: function(abTestService) { // abTestService is injected here
    var result = abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;); // Choose version A or B
    return &#39;...&#39;; // Return template content based on the result
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt; returns template content (not an URL to the template). We can certainly embed HTML markups directly in JavaScript, but for complicate HTML, it&amp;rsquo;s better to externalize the HTML content to separate template files. Here, we created &lt;code&gt;home-a.html&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;home-b.html&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;ngInclude&lt;/code&gt; them in the templateProvider function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- Home version A at app/home/home-a.html --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div ng-controller=&amp;quot;HomeAController&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Version A&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;!-- Home version B at app/home/home-b.html --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div ng-controller=&amp;quot;HomeBController&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Version B&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
  templateProvider: function(abTestService) {
    var result = abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;);

    // ngInclude template content based on the A/B test result
    return &#39;&amp;lt;div ng-include=&amp;quot;\&#39;app/home/home-&#39; + result + &#39;.html\&#39;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#39;;
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt; can also return a Promise which is resolved to template content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
  templateProvider: function($http, USER_SERVICE_REST_URL) {

    // Here, we return a promise instead of the template content
    return $http.get(USER_SERVICE_REST_URL).then(function(data) {
      var result = (data.type === &#39;member&#39; ? &#39;a&#39; : &#39;b&#39;);

      // Return the template content
      return &#39;&amp;lt;div ng-include=&amp;quot;\&#39;app/home/home-&#39; + result + &#39;.html\&#39;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#39;;
    });
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;even-better-solution:7c673880e38fa750461b975e7ddb6656&#34;&gt;EVEN BETTER SOLUTION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having &lt;code&gt;ngInclude&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt; function feels still a bit hackish to me. The ideal solution is to specify a template URL, and then let Angular fetch the content. However, sending separate HTTP requests just to fetch templates seems to be unnecessary web traffic. It will be better if the template content can be cached in the $templateCache service; and then, all I need to do is &lt;code&gt;$templateCache.get(&#39;templateUrl&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$stateProvider.state(&#39;home&#39;, {
  templateProvider: function(abTestService, $templateCache) {
    var result = abTestService.pick(&#39;a&#39;, &#39;b&#39;);

    // Retrieve the cached template content from $templateCache service
    return $templateCache.get(&#39;app/home/home-&#39; + result + &#39;.html&#39;);
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve this, we need a Gulp task to convert all HTML files under the app/ directory to JavaScript strings, and save the strings in $templateCache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// Load gulp and its plugins
var gulp = require(&#39;gulp&#39;);
var minifyHtml = require(&#39;gulp-minify-html&#39;);
var angularTemplateCache = require(&#39;gulp-angular-templatecache&#39;);


gulp.task(&#39;templates&#39;, function() {

  return cacheTemplates(&#39;src/app/**/*.html&#39;, &#39;app.template.js&#39;);

  function cacheTemplates(input, output) {
    return gulp.src(input) // Get all HTML files
      .pipe(minifyHtml({ // Minify HTML content first
        empty: true,
        spare: true,
        quotes: true
      }))
      .pipe(angularTemplateCache(output, { // Save minified strings to cache
        module: &#39;myApp&#39; // Setup $templateCache for Angular module &#39;myApp&#39;
      }))
      .pipe(gulp.dest(&#39;.tmp/templates/&#39;));

  } // /function cacheTemplates

});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, import the generated &lt;code&gt;template.js&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;.tmp/templates/app.template.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:7c673880e38fa750461b975e7ddb6656&#34;&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By leveraging the &lt;code&gt;templateProvider&lt;/code&gt; function that can be injected with dependencies, we are able to resolve template content based on run-time data. This technique is useful for switching among more than one templates for a state, for instance, A/B testing, and swappable content in limited space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directive Isolated Scope: @ vs. =</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/directive-at-vs-equal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/directive-at-vs-equal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Shall I use @ or = to bind scope variables? Their difference is very well explained in Angular&amp;rsquo;s documentation. However, this question still often pops up when I create directives. In this post, I listed some of the major differences between these two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interpolation-binding:a300ed22ee47617686df42dbda8a1336&#34;&gt;@: Interpolation Binding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;@&amp;rdquo; symbols can be used to bind interpolations. Interpolations are {{ }} expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a @-bound scope variable &amp;ndash; &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; in a directive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// A directive
function awesomeWidget() {
  return {
    ...
    scope: {
      name: &#39;@&#39; // @-bound variable
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now can assign interpolation &lt;code&gt;{{ person.name }}&lt;/code&gt; to the @-bound variable &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- Use interpolation {{ person.name }} for @-bound variables --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;{{ person.name }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what will happen if we replace &lt;code&gt;{{ person.name }}&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt;? Angular will not throw any error, but the value of &lt;code&gt;scope.name&lt;/code&gt; will be a &lt;code&gt;&#39;person.name&#39;&lt;/code&gt; string instead of the real value of person.name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also assign primitives (string, number, boolean, and etc.) directly to @-bound values. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;David&amp;quot; age=&amp;quot;26.5&amp;quot; single=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!-- Note: &amp;quot;David&amp;quot; here is a string primitive not a variable name --&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular is smart enough to figure out their types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;function awesomeWidget($log) {
  return {
    ...
    scope: {
      name: &#39;@&#39;, age: &#39;@&#39;, single: &#39;@&#39;
    },
    link: function(scope) {
      $log.log(scope.name, typeof scope.name);
      // --&amp;gt; &amp;quot;David&amp;quot;, string
      $log.log(scope.age, typeof scope.age);
      // --&amp;gt; 26.5, number
      $log.log(scope.single, typeof scope.single);
      // --&amp;gt; false, boolean
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;variable-name-binding:a300ed22ee47617686df42dbda8a1336&#34;&gt;=: Variable Name Binding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;=&amp;rdquo; symbols can be used to bind variable names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we have a =-bound variable &amp;ndash; &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;function awesomeWidget() {
  return {
    ...
    scope: {
      name: &#39;=&#39; // =-bound scope variable
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike @-bound variables which require interpolations such as &lt;code&gt;{{ person.name }}&lt;/code&gt;, =-bound variables can directly refer to variable names, e.g. &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;person.name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!-- Not {{ person.name }} --&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we replace &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;{{ person.name }}&lt;/code&gt;, Angular will throw an error this time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-plain&#34;&gt;Error: [$parse:syntax] Syntax Error:
Token &#39;{&#39; invalid key at column 2 of the expression [{{ person.name }}]
starting at [{ person.name }}].
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primitives can also be assigned to =-bound variables. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;awesome-widget age=&amp;quot;26.5&amp;quot; single=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for strings, single quotes are needed. This is different from @-bound values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;&#39;David&#39;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!-- Note: David is wrapped in single quotes --&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single quotes are needed because without the single quotes, Angular will treat &amp;ldquo;David&amp;rdquo; as a variable name instead of a string primitive, which might not be what you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-way-binding:a300ed22ee47617686df42dbda8a1336&#34;&gt;@: One-way Binding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@ is for one-way binding - the bound value is passed into a directive&amp;rsquo;s scope, however, any change made to the value inside the directive will not be passed back from the directive. To help myself remember this syntax, I&amp;rsquo;d like to think @ as &amp;lsquo;point at&amp;rsquo; - a one-way direction - from the external scope to a directive&amp;rsquo;s internal scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div ng-controller=&amp;quot;MainController&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;{{ person.name }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bind &lt;code&gt;{{ person.name }}&lt;/code&gt; to the directive through the &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; attribute. The value of &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt; comes from a person object that is attached to the &lt;code&gt;MainController&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s scope:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// A controller
function MainController($scope) {
  $scope.person = { name: &#39;David&#39; };
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the directive, the @ symbol is to indicate that &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; will be one-way bound to the directive&amp;rsquo;s scope variable &lt;code&gt;scope.name&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// A directive
function awesomeWidget() {
  return {
    ...
    scope: {
      name: &#39;@&#39; // One-way binding
    },
    link: function(scope) {
      // Here we change the name variable on the directive scope
      scope.name = &#39;Serena&#39;;
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we change the name variable inside the directive (e.g., in the link function), the changed name will not be passed back from the directive&amp;rsquo;s scope to the controller&amp;rsquo;s scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div ng-controller=&amp;quot;MainController&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;{{ person.name }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;!-- In the controller&#39;s scope, person.name will still be &amp;quot;David&amp;quot; instead of &amp;quot;Serena&amp;quot; --&amp;gt;
  {{ person.name }}
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside awesome-widget&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; function, name is changed from &amp;ldquo;David&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Sereana&amp;rdquo;. However, outside of the directive, &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt; is still &amp;ldquo;David&amp;rdquo;. This is because the scope variable &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; is one-way bound. The change will not affect the scope outside of its directive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-way-binding:a300ed22ee47617686df42dbda8a1336&#34;&gt;=: Two-way Binding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;= is for two-way binding, meaning the change made to the bound value will be &amp;ldquo;sync&amp;rsquo;d&amp;rdquo; both inside and outside of a directive. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think the &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; symbol as &amp;ldquo;bi-directional&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the above example, we change &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// A directive
function awesomeWidget() {
  return {
    ...
    scope: {
      name: &#39;=&#39; // Changed to two-way binding
    },
    link: function(scope) {
      scope.name = &#39;Serena&#39;;
    }
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that in the HTML template, we also changed &lt;code&gt;{{ person.name }}&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div ng-controller=&amp;quot;MainController&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;awesome-widget name=&amp;quot;person.name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/awesome-widget&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- Removed {{ }} --&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;!-- Now, person.name is changed to &amp;quot;Serena&amp;quot; --&amp;gt;
  {{ person.name }}
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scope variable &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; is changed in directive&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; function. Because &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; is two-way bound, the change is also reflected in &lt;code&gt;person.name&lt;/code&gt; on &lt;code&gt;MainControler&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:a300ed22ee47617686df42dbda8a1336&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Direction&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Value type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;String primitive&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;@&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One-way binding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Interpolations and primitives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No single quote: &amp;ldquo;David&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;=&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Two-way binding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Variable names and primitives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Single quotes: &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;David&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular Factory Pattern</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-factory-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-factory-pattern/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;suffix-factory-with-service:2125073d380548c4d6df7eb33c79e543&#34;&gt;Suffix Factory with &amp;lsquo;Service&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terminology &amp;ldquo;Factory&amp;rdquo; in Angular is different from the one used in the Java community. From a Java developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, a factory is to create something by a specification supplied by the factory caller. There should be only one public method on a factory - getInstance(). Well, maybe some variations of the getInstance method. But that should be it. Factories simply create stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in Angular, unlike &lt;code&gt;angular.controller&lt;/code&gt; which creates a controller, what &lt;code&gt;angular.factory&lt;/code&gt; creates is not a factory but a service - a place to host public APIs and encapsulate logics, not a factory that creates stuff. Services certainly could be used to create things, however, the most common usage is to wrap shared code and expose them to consumer code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;angular.factory&lt;/code&gt; returns a service singleton. That&amp;rsquo;s why I would like to suffix the factory function with &amp;ldquo;Service&amp;rdquo; not &amp;ldquo;Factory&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  // userService instead of userFactory
  .factory(&#39;userService&#39;, userService)
;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;decouple-interface-from-implementation:2125073d380548c4d6df7eb33c79e543&#34;&gt;Decouple Interface from Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common factory looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//
// Not so good
//
angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .factory(&#39;userService&#39;, userService)
;

function userService($http, $log) {

  // Private variables
  var REST_URL = &#39;/api/users&#39;;

  // Return the service instance
  return {

    // Public methods

    getUsers: function() { ... },
    queryUsers: function(by) { ... }
  };
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing is really wrong with the above example. However, there is room for improvement - the returned service instance is a congealment of both interface and implementation. &lt;code&gt;getUsers&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;queryUsers&lt;/code&gt; are interfaces, while their associated anonymous functions are implementation details. If the anonymous functions grow in lines of code, it would be &amp;ldquo;a bit&amp;rdquo; difficult to tell the service interface from implementations. To improve the readability, a common practice is to move the implementations out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//
// Better
//
function userService($http, $log) {

  ...

  // Move implementation here
  var getUsers = function() { ... };
  var queryUsers = function(by) { ... };

  // Keep interface simple
  return {
    getUsers: getUsers
    queryUsers: queryUsers
  };
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;move-declarations-to-top:2125073d380548c4d6df7eb33c79e543&#34;&gt;Move Declarations to Top&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push good readability further, I will move declarations above implementations, just like how we define Angular components. Here is an example of Angular controller definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//
// Good example
//
angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  // Controller declarations. We have two controllers
  .controller(&#39;MainController&#39;, MainController)
  .controller(&#39;SideBarController&#39;, SideBarController)
;

// Controller implementations
function MainController() { ... }
function SideBarController() { ... }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By moving declarations above Implementations, we have a clear manifest of what this Angular script will do. Apply the same principle to factories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//
// Improved
//
function userService($http) {

  // Declarations, moved up.
  return {
    getUsers: getUsers,
    queryUsers: queryUsers
  };

  // Implementations, moved down.
  // Use function declaration syntax instead of
  // var getUsers = function() { ... };
  function getUsers() { ... }
  function queryUsers(by) { ... }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we use function declaration syntax to define the implementation functions, so they will be hoisted and accessible even before they are defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also recommended to have variables defined at top of the function body:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;//
// Improved
//
function userService($http) {

  // Declarations
  var var1 = 1;

  return {
    getUsers: getUsers,
    queryUsers: queryUsers
  };

  // Implementations
  function getUsers() { ... }
  function queryUsers(by) { ... }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:2125073d380548c4d6df7eb33c79e543&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffix factories with &amp;lsquo;Service&amp;rsquo;. Leverage function hoisting to pull declarations above implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;;(function() {
  &#39;use strict&#39;;

  angular
    .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
    .factory(&#39;userService&#39;, userService) // Declaration
  ;


  function userService($http, $log) { // Implementation

    // Declaration

    var REST_URL = &#39;/api/users&#39;;

    return {
      getUsers: getUsers,
      queryUsers: queryUsers
    };

    // Implementation

    function getUsers() { ... }

    function queryUsers(by) { ... }
  }

})();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same style can be applied to other Angular components, such as directives and filters. Here is a directive example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;;(function() {
  &#39;use strict&#39;;

  angular
    .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
    .directive(&#39;myAwesomeWidget&#39;, myAwesomeWidget)
  ;


  function myAwesomeWidget($log) {

    // Directive declarations
    return {
      restrict: &#39;AE&#39;,
      scope: {
        options: &#39;=&#39;
      },
      templateUrl: &#39;app/common/myAwesomeWidget.html&#39;,
      link: linkMyAwesomeWidget
    };

    // Link function implementation
    function linkMyAwesomeWidget(scope, elem, attrs) {
      ...
    }
  }
})();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular Best Practice Recap</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-best-practice-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/angular-best-practice-recap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I attended a great Angular training provided by OasisDigital the last week. Learned so many tips and best practices from Bill Odom and his team. While my memory is still fresh, I&amp;rsquo;d like to document the stuff I learned. So again, I use my blog as study notes. While I&amp;rsquo;m on the topic of Angular best practices, I also like to bring in some advices from John Papa, Shai Reznik, and other wisdoms of the community. This article basically is a recap of what I heard and learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prefer-factory-over-service:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;PREFER FACTORY OVER SERVICE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A service is a simplified version of a factory. Services are a constructor functions. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some service code that returns objects. The author of the code probably mistook services with factories. To clear the confusion, let&amp;rsquo;s favor factories over services. I personally prefer naming a factory as xyzService instead of xyzFactory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .factory(&#39;fooService&#39;, fooService)
;

function fooService() {
  return {
    getFoo: function() { ... },
    getBar: function() { ... }
  };
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;assign-third-party-globals-to-values:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;ASSIGN THIRD-PARTY GLOBALS TO VALUES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I can use $window to reference globals of third-party libraries, I like to assign globals to values, and inject them. This makes function arguments a clear contract of what dependencies my code requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .value(&#39;_&#39;, _) // lodash
  .value(&#39;d3&#39;, d3) // D3
;

...

function MainController(_, d3) { // Injection
  _.forEach( ... );
  d3.select( ... );
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For low-level libraries (e.g., lodash), I can even delete lodash&amp;rsquo;s global &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo; from the window object, so &amp;lsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; will be available only through injection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .factory(&#39;_&#39;, function() {
    var _ = window._;
    delete window._; // Delete _ from window

    return _;
  })
;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stick-with-http:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;STICK WITH $HTTP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel $http gives me more flexibilities than $resource. And $http service&amp;rsquo;s promise interface is much nicer. Better to stick with $http than mixing $http and $resource which unnecessarily complicate my code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-rest-in-services:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;WRAP REST IN SERVICES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encapsulate REST requests as methods in services, so users of the service don&amp;rsquo;t have to know the interface of your REST APIs, and the choice of REST libraries ($http, $resource, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .factory(&#39;accountService&#39;, accountService)
;

function accountService($http, $log) {
  return {
    getAccounts: function(userId) {
      return $http.get(&#39;/api/accounts/&#39; + userId)
        .then(function(response) {
          return response.data;
        })
        .catch(function(error) {
          $log.error(error);
          return error;
        })
      ;
    }
  };
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ui-router-resolve-pattern:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;UI ROUTER RESOLVE PATTERN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often run to the scenarios where I need to hold off displaying UI until certain data is ready. The resolve property of uiRouter is designed to tackle this common problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assign a name-to-function map to the resolve property. If the function returns a value, the returned value is treated as dependency, and the value is injected into the controller; if the function returns a promise, the promise is resolved before the controller is instantiated, and the resolved value is injected into the controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$stateProvider
  .state(&#39;home&#39;, {
    ... ,

    // Resolve items and users before routing to the &#39;home&#39; state
    resolve: {
      items: function() {
        // Returns an array value
        return [
          { name: &#39;The Settlers of Catan&#39;, price: 51.46 },
          { name: &#39;Mansions of Madness&#39;, price: 56.52 }
        ];
      },
      users: function(userService) {
        // Returns a promise
        return userService.getUsers();
      }
    },

    // items and users are injected to the controller
    controller: function($scope, $log, items, users) {
      $log.log(items);
      $log.log(users);
    }
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;isolate-directive-scope:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;ISOLATE DIRECTIVE SCOPE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think Angular directives as re-usable functions, and its scope as the argument list of a function. In most cases, a directive shouldn&amp;rsquo;t assume the presence of data in the ancestor scopes or elements in the DOM. The scope (and the directive&amp;rsquo;s DOM attributes) should be the only place where a directive retrieves external information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pass information to directives via element attributes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div data-browse-happy-banner
  data-ie-version=&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;
  data-on-dismiss=&amp;quot;bannerDismissed()&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then retrieve these information from the scope:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .directive(&#39;browseHappyBanner&#39;, browseHappyBanner)
;

function browseHappyBanner() {
  return {
    restrict: &#39;A&#39;,
    scope: { // Isolated scope
      ieVersion: &#39;@&#39;, // Pass ieVersion from data-ie-version attribute
      onDismiss: &#39;&amp;amp;&#39; // Pass onDismiss callback from data-on-dismiss attribute
    },
    template: &#39;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;a data-ng-click=&amp;quot;onClose()&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#39;,
    ... ,
    link: function(scope) {
      // Retrieve ieVersion from scope
      var iev = parseInt(scope.ieVersion, 10);
      ...
      scope.onClose = function() {
        // Invoke onDismiss callback from the scope
        scope.onDismiss();  
      };
    }
  };
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-template:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;CLEAN TEMPLATE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If snippets in a template look like program, then you are doing it wrong. Templates need to be declarative, easy to understand for non-programmers. The best practice is to imagine your template is written by a web designer rather than a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will a web designer understand the following template?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div data-ng-class=&amp;quot;{
  &#39;error&#39;: ((bFormSubmitted || PersonalInfoForm.DOBmonth.$dirty) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; PersonalInfoForm.DOBmonth.$invalid) ||
            ((bFormSubmitted || PersonalInfoForm.DOBday.$dirty) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; PersonalInfoForm.DOBday.$invalid) ||
            ((bFormSubmitted || PersonalInfoForm.DOByear.$dirty) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; PersonalInfoForm.DOByear.$invalid ) || errorMapResult.birthdate,
  &#39;success&#39;: (PersonalInfoForm.DOBmonth.$dirty &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !PersonalInfoForm.DOBmonth.$invalid) &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
              (PersonalInfoForm.DOBday.$dirty &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !PersonalInfoForm.DOBday.$invalid) &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
              (PersonalInfoForm.DOByear.$dirty &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !PersonalInfoForm.DOByear.$invalid )}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  ...
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess no. Even developer might have hard time to understand this. Move the logic to controller or service, so the template becomes clean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div data-ng-class=&amp;quot;{ &#39;error&#39;: hasError, &#39;success&#39;: isSuccessful }&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  ...
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thin-controller:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;THIN CONTROLLER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make controller thin. Move logic to services and directives. This makes controller much easy to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;light-filter:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;LIGHT FILTER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filter tends to be called multiple times. So if you have a filter that does a lot of heavy lifting, it will drag down the performance of the entire app. Try to simplify the logic in filter. Use cache or memoization to improve the performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
angular
  .module(&amp;quot;myApp&amp;quot;)
  .filter(&amp;quot;heavyLifting&amp;quot;, heavyLifting) // A filter does heavy lifting stuff
;

function heavyLifting() {

  var doHeavyLifting = function() { ... }; // Complicate process

  // Use lodash&#39;s memoize function to cache the returned result for a specific input.
  // Future calls with the same input will return the cached result.
  return _.memoize(function(input) {
    return doHeavyLifting(input);
  });
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details on filter and memoization can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terrencewatson.com/2014/06/28/memoize/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;named-functions:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;NAMED FUNCTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use named functions whenever you can. When error occurs inside the named function, the function name will appear in the stack trace, which is really helpful for debugging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// Named function showToggle
$timeout(function showToggle() {
  angular.element(&#39;.toggle&#39;).css(&#39;display&#39;, &#39;block&#39;);
}, 1000);

// Named function greet
var greet = function greet(name) {
  console.log(&#39;Hello &#39; + name);
};

// Named controller
angular.module(&#39;myApp&#39;).controller(&#39;MyController&#39;, MyController);
function MyController() { ... }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-js-code-in-iife:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;SCOPE JS CODE IN IIFE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This best practice is not limited to Angular. IIFE (Immediately-Invoked Function Expression) is often used to create scopes in which the variables and functions will not be leaked to outer scopes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;;(function() {
  ...
  var app = angular.module(&#39;myApp&#39;);
  ...
})();

console.log(app) // not defined
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pyramid-testing:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;PYRAMID TESTING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again this advice is not limited to Angular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write more unit tests. Treat unit tests as front-line defense. Use e2e protractor tests as high-level tests for verifying critical happy and error paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Fowler discussed &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TestPyramid.html&#34;&gt;Test pyramid&lt;/a&gt; in his blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/pyramid.png&#34; alt=&#34;Test Pyramid&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ng-model-dot-rule:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;NG-MODEL DOT RULE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misko Hevery in his presentation on Angular best practices coined the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=ZhfUv0spHCY#t=1758s&#34;&gt;dot rule&lt;/a&gt;. My over-simplified version is to bind objects instead of primitives to $scope, and always initialize the bound object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;function MainController($scope) {
  $scope.something = {}; // Always initialize the bound objects

  $scope.person = {
    name: &#39;David Cai&#39;
  }; // Bind objects to $scope instead of $scope.name = &#39;David Cai&#39;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the HTML template:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;div ng-controller=&amp;quot;MainController&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;input ng-model=&amp;quot;person.name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-component-per-file:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;ONE COMPONENT PER FILE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limit one Angular component (directive, service, controller, etc.) per JavaScript file. Make it easy to locate components, and keep files shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;angular
  .module(&#39;myApp&#39;)
  .directive(&#39;myAwesomeWidget&#39;, function() { ... })

  // Don&#39;t.
  // We already defined a directive in this file.
  // Move the following directive to another file.
  .directive(&#39;myOtherAwesomeWidget&#39;, function() { ... })
;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;group-files-by-features:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;GROUP FILES BY FEATURES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two schools of thoughts when it comes to organizing Angular files - grouping by types, and grouping by features. I prefer the latter for big projects. Much easier for navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-plain&#34;&gt;common
  - util.filter.js
  - util.filter.spec.js
action-panel
  - action-panel.directive.js
  - action-panel.directive.spec.js
  - action-panel.html
  - action-panel.scss
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;include-intention-in-file-names:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;INCLUDE INTENTION IN FILE NAMES&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.js can mean a lot of things in Angular apps. It makes the intention much clear when the file names contain .controller, .directive, .spec, .service, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shai Reznik recommends using .ctrl for controllers, .drv for directives, .srv for services., .tpl for templates, and .test for unit tests. I prefer full names, e.g. .controller. I also feel that HTML files don&amp;rsquo;t need .tpl or .template, since in most cases, HTML files are templates. No need to explicitly call them out as templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lint-javascript:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;LINT JAVASCRIPT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use jshint, JSCS, or even better - &lt;a href=&#34;http://eslint.org/&#34;&gt;eslint&lt;/a&gt; to lint javascript code. Integrate lint into the build process. Use editor plugins to bring lint warnings and errors right in front of developers&amp;rsquo;s eyes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering to create GIT hook to block git pushes if lint reports any warnings or errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-ng-annotate:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;USE NG-ANNOTATE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular replies on the names of function arguments for dependency injection. However, JS minification will shorten argument names, which ruined Angular DI. To work around this issue, we either use the DI array syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// DI array syntax
app.controller(&#39;MainController&#39;, [&#39;$scope&#39;, &#39;$log&#39;, function($scope, $log) {
  ...
}]);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; or assign dependencies to the $inject property:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// $inject syntax
MainController.$inject = [&#39;$scope&#39;, &#39;$log&#39;];
function MainController($scope, $log) {
  ...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These workarounds look like patchwork to me. Not to mention that both are error prone where you have to maintain the dependency order in arrays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/olov/ng-annotate&#34;&gt;ngAnnotate&lt;/a&gt; - an Angular plugin that automatically inserts the DI array syntax in source code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;// ngAnnotate will replace function($scope, $log) { ... } with
// [&#39;$scope&#39;, &#39;$log&#39;, function($scope, $log) { ... }]
app.controller(&#39;MainController&#39;, function($scope, $log) {
  ...
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although ngAnnotate is quite smart to figure out where to annotate DI syntax, in some cases, ngAnnotate might miss the DI annotation for a function. You can prepend a function with &lt;code&gt;/*@ngInject*/&lt;/code&gt; to explicitly state that the function should get annotated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leverage-task-runners:55578ab064fd5af32026dc69791cd223&#34;&gt;LEVERAGE TASK RUNNERS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lint and ngAnnotate can be integrated in the build process by task runners such as Gulp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Gulp to automate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JS lint - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adametry/gulp-eslint&#34;&gt;gulp-eslint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ngAnnotate - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Kagami/gulp-ng-annotate&#34;&gt;gulp-ng-annotate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort angular files - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klei/gulp-angular-filesort&#34;&gt;gulp-angular-filesort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert HTML templates to JS strings in $templateCache - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/miickel/gulp-angular-templatecache&#34;&gt;gulp-angular-templatecache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s use NVM</title>
      <link>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/lets-use-nvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcai.github.io/blog/posts/lets-use-nvm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My colleague just came to me with a troubled face. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why his gulp script failed to start up local server where everyone else is able to do so. After a short debugging session, I found that the culprit is Node JS version. Certainly, our gulp scripts have a conflict with the latest Node JS. Now, my colleague has to downgrade his Node JS installation, or does he have to? :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this fast-moving industry, maintaining specific versions for your libraries or tools seems to be a chore. That&amp;rsquo;s why there are so many xyz managers, e.g. pip, apt-get, bower, npm, jspm, and homebrew, etc. For managing versions of Node JS, there is NVM - Node Version Manager. I highly recommend using it to have better controls of which version of Node I use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already installed Node via other installers, it&amp;rsquo;s better to completely remove the existing Node and NPM. To do that, I stole the following command from this stackoverflow thread - &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/11177954/how-do-i-completely-uninstall-node-js-and-reinstall-from-beginning-mac-os-x&#34;&gt;How do I completely uninstall Node.js, and reinstall from beginning (Mac OS X)&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;lsbom -f -l -s -pf /var/db/receipts/org.nodejs.pkg.bom | while read f; do  sudo rm /usr/local/${f}; done

sudo rm -rf /usr/local/lib/node /usr/local/lib/node_modules /var/db/receipts/org.nodejs.*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should remove all Node JS and NPM from Mac OS X. Now let&amp;rsquo;s install NVM. As of June 2015, the following might be the easiest command to install NVM:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;curl -o- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/creationix/nvm/v0.25.4/install.sh | bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: It&amp;rsquo;s always safe to check if &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/creationix/nvm&#34;&gt;NVM&lt;/a&gt; updated their installation command.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The install.sh script will insert a few lines to ~/.bashrc, however, Mac OS X for some reason won&amp;rsquo;t source ~/.bashrc (&lt;a href=&#34;http://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/119711/why-mac-os-x-dont-source-bashrc&#34;&gt;see details&lt;/a&gt;). So we have to copy the inserted lines to ~/.bash_profile instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Node version manager
export NVM_DIR=&amp;quot;/Users/your_username/.nvm&amp;quot;
[ -s &amp;quot;$NVM_DIR/nvm.sh&amp;quot; ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; . &amp;quot;$NVM_DIR/nvm.sh&amp;quot;  # This loads nvm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change your_username to your home dir name. After sourcing ~/.bash_profile, NVM will be loaded and ready to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;source ~/.bash_profile
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s install Node JS, for example, version 0.10.38:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;nvm install 0.10.38
nvm use 0.10.38
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type &lt;code&gt;node -v&lt;/code&gt; to check if the correct version is installed and in use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node 0.10.38 is installed. However, it will be a bit tedious to type &lt;code&gt;nvm use 0.10.38&lt;/code&gt; to switch to that version every time a terminal session starts. To fix that, I assign &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo; as an alias to v0.10.38:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;nvm alias default 0.10.38
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versions tied to the &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo; alias will be the default active version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are free to install many versions of Node JS with NVM. For instance, here we install the stable version (0.12.4 as of June 2015):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;nvm install stable
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To list all installed Node Js, and see which one is active, use the &lt;code&gt;nvm ls&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://davidcai.github.io/blog/img/nvm-ls.png&#34; alt=&#34;nvm ls&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command reports that I have v0.10.38 and v0.12.4 installed. The current active version is 0.10.38. I have four aliases - default, node, sable, and iojs. Aliases can refer to other aliases. In this example, node refers stable, and stable refers 0.12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:873ad2aa58948dc097de69876bea24cc&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing versions is crucial but tedious. The task should be automated. NVM helps us manage multiple Node Js versions without a sweat. It becomes much easy to work in a working version, and try something new in the latest version. All I have to do is &lt;code&gt;nvm use default&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nvm use stable&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a side benefit is that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to &lt;code&gt;sudo npm install&lt;/code&gt; any more. Just &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>